Ju-on: The curse of one who dies
in the grip of powerful rage.
It gathers and takes effect in
the places that person was alive.
Those who encounter it die,
and a new curse is born.
JU-ON: The Grudge
Rika
Social Welfare Center
I'm back.
Hello.
Write your name and the time
in here, please.
All right.
There.
Thanks.
Rika!
It's this.
What? By myself?
There's no one else around.
But...
Whose case is it?
I can't reach him.
He took the key and left,
and hasn't come back.
I'm just a volunteer...
That's all right.
You're used to this.
Mr Hirohashi...
Mr Goto's looking for you.
Goto?
Would you do it?
Just look in on her.
But...
I'll buy you dinner.
You don't have to...
Tokunaga
Hello?
Hello!
I'm from the Welfare Center...
May I come in?
Are you all right?!
You're Sachie, right?
I'm here to help out
in place of Mr Takahashi.
I'm Nishina Rika.
Come on...
Come here...
Sachie!
Who's that boy upstairs?!
He was shut in a closet!
You didn't say anything
about a child.
Yes. He's still upstairs.
Yes.
I told you, they aren't home yet!
But...
Yes.
All right.
There's no one home right now.
Please leave a message.
Hello? It's Hitomi.
Hello? Kazumi, are you there?
How's Mom getting along?
I'm a bit worried,
so please give me a call.
Um, what's your name?
Toshio.
Yeah? 'Toshio'...
My name's...
I told her.
Sachie?
I told Kazumi.
I told her again and again.
What's the matter?
Why don't you lie down, OK?
Again and again, I told her.
Just the way you said to.
Please stop tormenting me.
Sachie...
Katsuya
Morning.
Mom sure sleeps late these days.
That's 'cause she's up all night.
Every night.
I'm sure it's fine for someone
who can sleep through anything.
Maybe it was the move.
I'll talk to the helper.
We're paying for him, after all.
That won't help. Your mother's
always nice with other people.
OK, OK. Try to get along, will you?
You'll be home early?
Your sister's coming!
You forgot!
Is it Friday already?
Get it together.
Hurry home.
OK. See you.
Oh, Mother!
Just tell me if you want something!
Who's that?
Who's there?
I'm home!
Is Hitomi here?
Kazumi?
Mom?
Where's Kazumi?
Where is she?!
Kazumi!
Kazumi?
Are you here?
Kazumi!
Hey! Kazumi!
What's wrong? What happened?
What?
Hang on. I'll call an ambulance.
What are you doing here?!
Kazumi!
Hello!
Hello? I'm here!
Kazumi?
Hi, Mom. How are you?
Where's Kazumi?
I'll start getting dinner ready.
Kazumi? Is that you?
Katsuya?
Don't scare me like that!
Where's Kazumi?
Kazumi went out. Something came up.
She's not shopping?
She'll be back soon, won't she?
I'm sorry, Hitomi.
This isn't a very good time.
What's going on?
Did something happen?
She had another man.
What?!
She deceived me!
That's not my child.
What are you talking about?!
Look, just go away, OK?
Are you feeling all right?
I'm fine.
Just leave me alone for a while.
Hitomi
There's no one home right now.
Please leave a message.
Hello? It's Hitomi.
Hello? Kazumi, are you there?
How's Mom getting along?
I'm a bit worried,
so please give me a call.
Tokunaga Katsuya
Hello, Katsuya?
I just called your house.
Hello? Katsuya?
Look, this isn't funny!
Sorry. I just hung up.
Who's there?
The 5th-floor Ladies'?
Yes.
I'll go take a look.
You wait here.
Excuse me!
Yes?
Hello? It's me.
Katsuya?
I'm out front of your building.
What number were you?
702! Hurry, will you?
Katsuya!
...also a house bat,
a pygmy woodpecker...
...wild birds not seen here before,
a blue-green snake...
...among 54 discoveries, including
a 2.5- Meter discarded snakeskin...
Toyama
Hello?
Missus?
Rika?
Rika!
Mr Nakagawa...
Dial him.
Up there.
Rika...
Rika!
Are you OK?
Yeah. Sorry, Mariko.
You're missing school.
That's OK.
I've got all the credits I need.
Anyway, what happened?
I don't really understand
that myself.
Was Hirohashi bugging you
to do something again?
And you couldn't say no?
You're supposed to be
the care-giver!
I'm glad you came.
I'll go buy a drink.
So that was the first time
you'd been there?
Yes, it was.
About the child
you say you saw there...
Did you find him?
No... not yet.
'Toshio'...
He said his name was Toshio.
Toshio?
Ms Nishina, the Tokunagas
don't have any children.
What?
What about that photograph?
There was a family picture
in the house.
That wasn't the Tokunagas.
Then who was it?
We're looking into that.
Detective...
What happened there?
Excuse me.
The families before the Tokunagas
all died or disappeared, too.
Is this all of them?
What about the sister?
We can't find her.
A security guard
where she works is dead, too.
And...
...look at this.
A man named Saeki Takeo
killed his wife Kayako there.
Later he was found dead
on the road by a neighbor.
Saeki Kayako, 28, housewife.
She and Takeo had a son.
'Toshio'...
Kayako's body was found...
...up there under the roof.
Hi, Daddy!
Hi, lzumi. Where's Mom?
Shopping.
She'll be angry again
if you don't get home.
It's OK. Come over here.
Why?
Come on!
Quick!
What is it?
Look at this.
Did you draw those?
Yep!
This is the Prince of Heaven.
That's the Princess.
And that's their baby.
Yeah? And who's this?
Mr Toyama Yuji? Lgarashi,
Yahara Division.
Ow!
What is it?
You were in charge of the
Saeki investigation.
I'd like to talk to you.
Izumi, you get on home.
I quit the force.
Leave me alone, will you?
Two more people have died there.
You're the only one left
who was involved with the case.
Izumi! What are you doing there?
Did you clean the bath?
It's your turn today, you know.
Get going.
Was this the boy you saw
at the Tokunaga house?
Yes.
Take a good look.
You're sure?
Yes, it was him. Did you find him?
No.
He went missing five years ago.
He's never been found.
Even if he were alive somewhere,
he'd be 11 years old.
Huh?
Mr Nakagawa...
This is Toyama Yuji.
He was on that case.
Thank you.
My name's Nakagawa. Come in.
Tokunaga Hitomi. Her elder brother
Katsuya lived in that house.
She went home, then disappeared.
Someone in her building
saw her come home.
They found Hirohashi's body.
The man who found Rika is dead.
Mr. Toyama.
Would you excuse me a minute,
please?
Lzumi, you're chicken!
What's that?
Sake.
What's that doing here?
Saori, you pig!
That's not sake.
I'm leaving!
Wait! It's OK!
Are you running out?
Lzumi!
What a suck!
She's always like that.
Yeah, and I heard...
...now she hangs with Chiharu.
He hasn't come home.
Where could he be?
Well? She's gone, you know.
Can you believe that!
Ayano, check out the window.
She's there.
She's by the gate.
It looks like she's thinking.
Why's she so scared?
Maybe she's got ESP.
She didn't have to leave!
I'm cold.
Yeah.
What was that?
What's wrong?
Lzumi's gone!
What?
Mr Toyama!
Mr Nakagawa!
Please!
Get a grip!
What happened?!
Lzumi
What's 1 st period?
English?
Mr Sekine!
Oh, yuck!
His English is weird!
Yeah!
It doesn't sound like
any English I've heard.
Do foreigners understand him?
He probably can't speak it!
Yeah, but he's teaching it to us!
Lzumi?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Missing
Isn't she lzumi?
She is not.
Find one?
Not yet.
'Bye.
Mr Sekine!
What's up?
Toyama? What's wrong?
There's no picture of lzumi.
Why not?
That shouldn't be. Did you look?
There isn't.
We looked and looked and looked!
I see.
OK, I'll check the negatives.
Can you wait a while?
'Bye.
How long?!
Don't pull!
You'll stretch my sweater!
Within a week.
Why a week?!
I'm a busy man!
A woman's body has been found
in an empty house in Nerima ward.
Nishina Rika,
a 23 year-old social worker...
...had been listed as missing.
No marks were found on the body.
Thank you.
Finally!
It's not my fault!
We're going to lzumi's.
OK, I'll come with you.
Hey!
No, thanks. 'Bye.
We'll bring them back tomorrow.
Talk to Toyama for me!
Let me see!
No!
We'll see them with lzumi.
But I want to see them!
You're lzumi's friends?
Lzumi? It's Chiharu and Miyuki.
We brought the pictures.
Can we come in?
Isn't it a bit dark in here?
Don't!
Lzumi?
What's wrong?
The three of them are looking in...
...at me.
'The three of them'?
Saori and the rest.
The night they disappeared,
I was with them.
Then why didn't...
I was scared!
Scared of what?
When we came back
from the school trip...
...Saori said...
...there was a haunted house
near here.
Haunted?
Where?
I forget!
How could you forget?
I wanted to!
Lzumi,
will you tell us what's going on?
Even before we went in...
...I felt something strange.
Izumi, do you have ESP or something?
I don't.
It's not that.
You guys keep away.
Saori and the others treated it as
a joke, but I couldn't stay there.
I left, by myself.
I was scared. I ran away.
They're coming for me!
Lzumi, chill out!
Close the curtains!
Close them!
Close them!!
That's what my husband was like
before he died.
He had all the windows
closed tight...
Does lzumi know about that?
I never told her anything about it.
The pictures...
What's that?
Chiharu!
Who are you?
Dad?
I saw you at that house, you know.
Kayako
Hello?
Mariko! It's been ages!
Yeah. What's up?
Yeah.
Wow, that must have been hard.
Peek-a-boo!
Tomorrow? Yeah, I'm OK.
Yeah, OK.
OK, see you.
I'm coming, Mr Saito.
I hear you're going to be
a great-grandfather!
Peek-a-boo!
Mr Saito?
Thank you.
Rika!
Mariko!
How have you been?
You've changed your hair.
I got it cut.
Are you free Sunday?
Sunday? Sure.
Yeah?
He gave me two tickets...
...and said to take you.
Really?
What?
In third year you liked Toyoshima,
didn't you.
Huh?
It was all over your face.
There's already one problem kid...
in my new class.
He hasn't come to school once!
And his parents?
That's the problem.
I can't contact them.
Well,
there must be some kind of reason...
At least they could return my calls.
I want to finish my home visits!
Oh, yeah... home visits...
All the other teachers
have finished theirs.
That's funny.
What is?
You're turned into a real teacher.
What about you?
I wonder about that.
I don't really understand...
What?
I thought I felt...
Rika? Are you OK
Rika!
Rika, what's wrong?! Are you OK?
Uh, yeah...
Hello, Nishima.
Rika?
Mariko? I'm sorry about today.
You scared me! Are you all right now?
Yeah. Thanks for asking.
I'm sorry I ruined your day off.
No, I'm OK.
Where are you now?
Remember that kid I told you about?
I'm at his house now.
Yeah...
There's no one here but the boy.
His parents haven't come home.
I've been here for an hour.
Mariko, where exactly are you?
Hello?
Hello, Rika?
Hey. Rika!
Toshio?
Are you up here?
Mariko!
Mariko...
Mariko?
No!